# Muhammad Rafli Indrawan, S.Kom

# **Website Developer**

#### **Profile**

My name is Muhammad Rafly Indrawan, A Programmer and IT Enthusiast who domiciled in Yogyakarta, 22 years old, love coding from senior high school, already handle 35+ websites with 5 years professional experience. love challenge and new / strange things. currently focused on learning Al, especially machine learning.

# **Work Experience**



# Chief Technology Officer | PT. Ide Jualan Creative | Yogyakarta

May 2020 to May 2023 (3 years)

- Lead IT Maintance Division
- Implementing Kanban methodology on development
- Lead IT Research & Development Team
- Designing Application Architecture & Stacks
- Documenting Waterfall modeled Feature
- Documenting DDD type research module
- Automating QA and AT
- Interviewing & Technical Test candidate
- Code restfull API for backend Stacks
- Maintain Server & Load Balance All Server Orchestra



## Senior Backend Developer | PT. Era Resolusi Pintar Indonesia | Jakarta

Sept 2022 to April 2023 (8 months)

- Creating Feature based on kanban with Laravel
- Maintaining AWS Server
- Maintaining Continous Integration & Continous Deployment

# LinkedIn Profile: linkedin.com/in/fliw

fliw@digitalkode.com +62 8812 6710 57 https://fliw.github.io Sleman, Yogyakarta

## **Skills & Specialization**

### - Framework -

- Laravel
- React JS
- Ionic

#### - Library -

- Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- MaterialUI

#### - Deployer -

- Vercel
- Netlify
- Heroku

#### - CI & CD -

Github Action

#### Package Manager -

- NPM
- Composer

#### – Database -

- MySQL / MariaDB
- MongoDB

#### Server

- Vultr Cloud VPS
- AWS EC2
- AWS Lambda

#### **Education History**



## Bachelor of Informatics | Universitas AMIKOM Yogyakarta

Class of 2023 | 2019-2023

• G.P.A 3.60



Software Engineering | SMK IT Al-Fath Sukabumi

Class of 2019 | 2018-2019

# **Work Experience**



## Lead Developer | PT. Naisha Inspirasi Muslimah | Yogyakarta

June 2020 to July 2021 (1 Year)

- Lead Team Project
- Documenting Feature Design
- Documenting Timeline Waterfall per Backlog
- Create Dashboard, Front SPA & Mobile apps



#### Co-Founder | DigitalKode | Sukabumi

April 2019 to July 2021 (1 Year 2 Months)

- Designing Application for Client
- Creating SaaS and one-Time payment project
- Pitching deck to many Client
- Leading IT Team creating Apps for Client

# **Organization**



Assistant | Lab Assistant Forum | Universitas AMIKOM Yogyakarta 2021-2021



IT Department | AMIKOM Computer Club | Universitas AMIKOM Yogyakarta

2019-2021

## **Public Speaker**



DSC Yogyakarta | Google Developer Student Clubs

Pre-Render Routes with react-snap



# Startup Talk | AMIKOM Business Park

Ultimate guide to creating a perfect Founding team

## **Commercial Project Experience**



# Project Manager | PT. Kirim Paket Integrasi | Yogyakarta | 2022

- Creating Kanban Waterfall for team
- Lead and Maintaining Programmer based on Kanban
- Help Backend Engineer to Code



# Project Manager & Backend | FanyBaby ITC Kuningan | Jakarta | 2023

- Lead and Maintaining Programmer based on Kanban
- Create Restfull Laravel API with swagger docs
- Deploy & Automate CICD to Server



## Backend Engineer | PT. Kampus Jualan Edutech | Yogyakarta | 2022-2023

- Create & Improving Features on Kampusjualan App
- Maintain Server



# Fullstack Engineer | BelanjaDiRumah.id | Yogyakarta | 2020

- Create Simple E-Commerce Apps
- Integrasi with third party API such as Rajaongkir



# CV. Oniversal Indonesia | Bandung | 2019

Remote Fullstack Web Developer |

- Designing Feature on E-Commerce
- Implement Feature on E-Commerce Oniversal



# Remote Fullstack Web Developer | Capcuzz | Yogyakarta | 2019

- Designing Feature on E-Commerce
- Create Simple E-Commerce Apps

# **Organizational Project Experience**



# IT Team | AMIKOM Computer Club | Yogyakarta | 2020-2021

- Maintain & Improve Feature on Competition of Developers's Website
- The Web was based on Laravel
- Maintain 2 Project, CODE 2020 & 2021



# IT | SMK IT Al-Fath | Sukabumi | 2018

 Create Simple Landing Page for School

# **Personal Project Experience**



### Qur'an of the day

- Hit Open API of Qur'an
- Provide Simple Interface who want to get randomized Qur'an Verses with arabic, latin, indonesian



### **Islamic PWA Apps**

 Create PWA Website with various menu such as Hadith, prophet stories, Prayers, prayer intention, Asmaul Husna, Ceramah



### Hadith of the day

- Hit Open API of Hadith
- Provide Simple Interface who want to get randomized Hadith with arabic, latin, indonesian



#### **Personal Website**

- Create Various Version of my own personal website
- total created 4 version of my own personal website, including the latest on https://fliw.github.io